I just dreaming everything you do is
public and you gotta be careful what you
click
go back and let's go cheer now to be
number one let's try this weekly top
Cheers
all right
ah so we have to learn what Levenberg
mark locks
[Music]
so you guys know that we're using g2o
and this is what it says g2o is a
general framework for graph optimization
but we're gonna write our on a brush my
nodes and edges of a graph so I suspect
that under the hood G - o is just
turning things into large matrices
yeah
let's refactor this a little bit
move all the out here
what up I'm ROG passing phrase the
points six points that sounds pretty
good idea myself doc frames local frames
if fixed points else self dot frames is
that right why did I write that
definitely move this up here
or have-nots in local frames if
fixpoints Elsa self dot freedoms okay so
you might actually need the local frame
logic here we might just get rid of this
well so there's another way to do this
right you don't actually have to pass in
the frames we could just pass in the
points and the frames we'll get at it
habla moss suerte see rapido fuerte
Ty Lee yong-dae know at the end a square
test no conozco that's that's my high
school Spanish
well the windows not defined now because
I use - no way no
self's I'm gonna have to pass in
max-frame
no see I don't like this no okay we have
to think this through better when I
stabbed it mom that's what I do mark go
investigate for you keyframes oh we're
gonna talk about keyframes bull how
chunk with Jing wind wailing wailing
wailing wailing now ye earth son sir
whoo y'all
that's all my shine you guys okay so if
we're actually gonna do this let's take
this through more right this okay come
on yo bro you guys should cheer
so we really did have an optimized here
yo come get yo just post in uh whatever
this is you can cheer and I get money
weekly top Cheers
new Tom Cruise cheer your way to the top
you learn the sequel's bros
well
so here's a thing to kind of think about
what properties do these things really
have frames and whether they're fixed or
not now we don't want to add a frame to
the graph if it has no points I mean
that's the other way to do this right
like I could actually just insert the
points at each
tell sense is a lovely girl but if we
don't agree they won't get a copyright
strike okay
the optimizer and we are doing need I
think we really need Kay I wonder if
it'll work better if I pass in the
points as it's at work
there's passing a null camera matrix we
can try that so like we're using KP use
right we can use KP s and then we can
for the camera so this is not alt just
pass it in a1100 it's how that works
it's pressing verbose the optimizer know
we have work works later this is twitch
time you look the errors are much much
smaller I don't know if that's better or
not they actually look identical that's
on a different scale
all right so maybe that'll be the new
way we do things we will pass in the KP
use will get rid of this no we don't
need decay anymore
what we're creating a class don't extend
from object but is that bad
- three class
you just want me to write that
save your ATP and all that means Wow
okay is the optimizer better but I just
saw it the air get really low but no
it's
no it's like just go to new room oh no
the bad okay
well save all works should I get rid of
all I really don't think it does
anything different at all
look at the air go down
okay by the way think about in terms of
that is probably better then we can move
the optimizer to here we'll put these
guys up here I don't know why Gigi oh
really does want you to put the camera
in it
well okay so what if I say for ID ID O's
frame that's a little annoying
because fight ok then I'm going to need
my own representation of the points
this whole local window thing is
annoying but maybe that is a parameter
to the optimizer the putting back should
probably be outside of the optimizer
okay so that's all moved GG oh
add the frame to graph that's alright
points to frame at edges okay now that's
the thing we don't really want to
probably only because we've indexing
you set this array frames are all still
in order at least we don't have like an
index array no I'm Sam well not sure
this isn't that bad
see I don't want to put the frames back
here I want to like pass that just the
optimizer right
okay so this is you don't first off this
all crap is stupid I'm not maintaining
this like to refactor it even better
than this though
we still like passing in these arbitrary
stupid frames and Des Moines classes so
we can get rid of this error then
doesn't as much meaning that's okay yeah
I thought GPRO was kind of shitty anyway
because like okay what did that even
mean by two pixels that's gonna change
the color
guys like this
pruning is bad with the per hour right
guys I need you to cheer or do whatever
happens on Twitch so I can make money
because otherwise you know who's gonna
fund these twitch streams that's right
which is not free you know somebody's
got to pay for it the bandwidth you
might just have to lower the stream
quality that's right
someone's got to pay for that I'm gonna
say me just tell us well for the future
how was our help STD man it's bad type
ID oh did I mess up my refactor or
something did I mess up troll mods give
you my troll mods wrong up Dan edge bad
check X Y Z the STD bad type binding
Oh so today I go with the alt one or not
the all one don't want to not be all
want to deleted the camera for
everything and that's why it's
complaining yeah well with the all
coding where you guys can't see either
I'm really terrible I'm sorry quick
peace I know I've let you down I know
this is why nobody donates to my channel
and poor so s is just not what he used
oh wait I already did that Wow it's
literally already exactly that function
great minds think alike you know not
cool
take your clothes off just dip it off
then why there yeah donate come on oh
gee Hasani yeah y'all bro I don't know
what that is but I think that means I
get money I love money guys money's
little my favorite things in the world
uh you know I love money
all right we factor out I did soon we're
gonna try to write our own optimizer
today and yeah we're going to Taylor
Swift is building a giant wall all right
guys
should we be real on this channel no I
don't know if we could be real on this
channel no no we can't be real we can't
be real no one gave me enough money yet
oh to people that money I don't
even know guys how does twitch work how
does twitch money work ah perfect
they're really showing hard de stream
how much could you reasonably expect to
make and just where does all this money
come from anyway so here we go you're a
smaller time twitch streamer will focus
on twitch since they're a market leader
right now you're just getting started
and through a combination of good
gameplay trancing charisma
and devilishly good looks you built up a
small base of viewers congratulations if
you got up to 54 he sent me a pyramid I
don't know what that means much
more important is that it gives you
additional monetization on ah one of the
most significant ones subscriptions a
little differently when they do on sites
like YouTube although streams are free
to view some fans choose to subscribe to
strangers that they like haha not only
supports the streamer financially but
gives the subscriber perks like special
emoji and badges for use in the chatroom
as well as the ability to watch streams
without any twitch advertisements so at
the time of writing twitch subscriptions
cost between five and twenty five US
dollars per month Wow how much the
viewer wants to pay with that money
being split half half between the
streamer and the twitch player and
viewers can also purchase what are
called bits alright guys this is not
good content we have to show good
content on this channel we are going to
be a number 1000 twitch channel I don't
understand yeah no they of course it is
man like you know let me tell you
something I used to be a cam girl um and
yeah you have to let your body's like my
free cam dollars ya Bryce well you know
sent the carrier pigeon no I know no
we're gonna be we're gonna be good guys
we're gonna write good quality okay
well so this mean is now long because
this is in terms of I don't know what a
good error function actually is there
should we do something like just call a
certain amount of points or Pierre this
is greater than zero service no it seems
pretty good
why is it - damn so expensive because we
love money if we didn't love money it
would be cheaper but we love money
what's the problem
but we really not to talk in
self-driving cars on this channel we
talk about slam and we're about to write
Levenberg mark Watts fix
you know the scrolling backwards on this
computer so then when I go to normal
computers I'm confused
okay so let's think about the problem
we're frames we have points and we want
to determine relationships between them
so my guess is what this actually
becomes is a really big oh hell yeah
quill fir'd yeah yeah I have seen I have
seen people do this before so I like I
watch I know what I watched on Twitch i
watch mario 64 120 star speedrunning and
yeah yeah okay by the way is anyone
there going to another pyramid man
is anyone going to the cvpr I'm thinking
about going if I make enough money on
Twitch to afford my cbpr travel that's
my dream man
send me the cvpr I know it's not like
super good games done quick or whatever
but but cvpr bro make enough money to
send me the cvpr
okay no no we have to focus on content
quality we can't just come on Twitch and
talk about how we want money that's not
good quality content
neither is saying that so that's a
problem I'll be right back to Reggie's
you want to support from Trump
so what we want to do is we want to take
this reprojection error and we want to
make it into like a flat matrix which I
think we can do right like we can just
flatten it out it's a three by F dot
pose P dot modulus no bro livestream
hacking that'll get too many viewers
okay we gotta think about what we want
to do but I don't know about Levenberg
mark walk but we were looking at mr.
iBooks here I was looking here at uh
applied linear algebra nice squares so
it is it's a least squares format
suppose that an M by M matrix is a tall
so that the system of linear equations
is over determined so we're gonna need
an over determined system of linear
equations yeah
I mean I think I could just stack the
poses and stack the points can i but the
real game is so we have to figure out
what we want to optimize we have to put
it in the format of least squares
somehow g2o is doing this such that I
know it's nonlinear least squares -
which was even worse somehow they're
doing it such that the pose and the
points get optimized see them sad this
is really so right here is actually all
the things we need to optimize let's
just comment this out for now this looks
like we don't use an optimizer at all
wow it sadly looks similar one on our
brakes no brakes yes we go now but
Boas sub-3 well that's okay we want to
simultaneously solve for all of these
projection equations now we could
optimize each point independently in
terms of least squares but that wouldn't
jointly optimize the poses and the
points at the same time like I'm really
I'm really just not sure how to do this
right do I write out two matrices and
like like ping-pong kind of back and
forth I mean maybe that's what it does
damply squares is used to solve
non-linear least squares problems
seems like a generic way to solve
nonlinear least squares problems
like do you see the problem like it will
try to matrices like I could put the
pose okay maybe maybe the G to L papers
talked about this
and I know I have to make the papers
bigger so you guys forego this example
illustrates how to represent an
objective function by a graph now I
could write an objective function I mean
okay so maybe that's just the idea maybe
first we just write an objective
function and then after we figure out
how to optimize that I mean the whole
objective function I want to optimize is
just this but like spread out a lot more
right so what is what function
okay
let's say I put my points over there and
we want to make this thing equal to zero
all right so we'll stack well stack all
my points in one water that stack all
large actually just like Python debugger
there well that's great thanks broski Oh
kiss my toes optimizer ground truth step
Wow the documentation is not up to date
bros spit a poor request
okay that's good so this is a beautiful
a beautiful long vector of points which
is all the points in our system now
okay so we want to minimize projection -
UV that I'm not exactly sure how to do
like how do I subtract UV but I won't
put the UVs over there so now P DB yeah
yeah I know okay we kind of helped we
kind of have three things right kind of
have the map points the points and the
frames there's probably some clever
thing that we can do to put like two of
them together but I don't see it off the
top of my head
if we didn't want to optimize the poses
it would be pretty easy what kind of
object is UV so UV is just the U and the
V it's just two numbers it's though it's
the coordinate in the image I'm in this
case the normalized coordinate in the
image right so and we could do all those
projections right you can project the
point according to the pose we would
expect that to equal UV okay so that
could just be me nigga so let's see what
a least-squares function looks like that
minimize okay okay okay okay so you have
this matrix system a times x equals B so
I think B is actually just all the
actual uese stack oh you can't say PDF
sorry just that oh my god is that okay
so that's all the UVs when they're
flattened so now we need a matrix times
a vector that will get us that which
[Music]
this term and this is the term that
makes it nonlinear slicey yeah it's for
two bits yeah bro I don't even know how
to watch ads but oh man I'm loving that
scoreboard
I love twitch let's say there's this
problem too
there's the problem of this stupid
non-linearity here this is not actually
linear system
there's no way to really make this a
linear system on my there warp slim
talks briefly about what they do for
linearization but the stupid / is not a
linear Broz there's no way I can just
write this as a matrix equation if we
insert all vectors in the datum throw I
don't know what you talk about sometime
okay linear least-squares derivation of
the normal equations yeah this is
actually a you do least squares but I'm
just talking about setting up the
problem I mean okay you know what let's
just use sci-fi pls sck whoa no no no
there's another side pie there's also
Syfy these squares this
okay function which computes the vector
of residuals right so actually I think
this is much easier than I think I think
we just actually have to do this okay
port B squared oh this is actually
really easy because no I know exactly
what all right okay so what we want to
do is least squares upon B B is my
target right and now I just need to
write the equation that generates that
so I should need to do the projection
here that just builds the UV matrix and
for fun
minimize f of X so that is a question of
like exactly what I'm trying to optimize
I don't know what X is yet and get to
that in a minute for now we just know
basically we want to write this so given
the residuals f of X minimize f of X
subject to some crap
okay there's three squares fun be
alright
get our get Q residuals now we can
figure out like that faster probably
[Music]
let's try that okay fun take zero
positional arguments but one was given
see that's what I don't understand
okay so that's an initial guess well
okay
oh I think we're you actually so well
for so it's got flat hand that's lesson
- B you don't need to be there we need X
right and then what is X well what if I
just yeah okay so I guess that thing I
was doing at the points is kind of right
what if I just put the points there in
terms of X instead of points homogeneous
yeah so get point location guesses this
is only gonna optimize the points guys
so call this X zero
this is a gas right and then that's what
we pass into there so instead of saying
P dot let's say we're gonna say x times
four times X is not defined yes be zero
wow oh wow oh oh it worked
eventually it just took 27 years it
returned something kind of absurd it's a
little absurd looking do you think well
no actually what was X is zero but that
should optimize all the points right
the only problem is right now we're
leaving the poses is fixed oh and those
poses are really crappy one of those
poses so crappy Oh weird using our PI
oops not use our PI which is actually
this is actually okay that we're just
doing this because we have the gun truth
poses okay 27 years great this probably
way to not make it take 27 vector of
residuals a function of shape and never
scale you've almost you're trying to one
D or F or shape M that's okay yeah
that's right
let's just say verbose equals wise here
we go yeah I know I know all about
Taylor bro
no you can do even better than if our
BOCES needs a to see what's going on
scam
you know brutally slow so I passed in
verbose equal to two by using the LM
method Oh LM is that Levenberg mark wat
all Levenberg mark why doesn't handle
bounce and sparsh jacobians trust region
reflective algorithm what's up little
countin never oh my god this is taking
forever
yeah how slow this is taking oh no I
have a phone call today
oh it did an iteration great
[Music]
I have to do a phone call at new Andros
this is so slow I've got our own tassel
love making money bus love mine
okay I see why that's slow probably
we're gonna make that function faster
Livia
Oh soft l-1a Huber loss Olaf Huber loss
oh that's great let's just humor loss
maybe that'll work back i don't be good
to outliers right here except it still
takes forever how gonna make this not
take forever well I think I can stack
all those poses right feel like robust
equals two made things just take way too
long
just a - right now really just in time
bro you almost gotta - night okay
[Music]
19:01 times for now that's not right I
think I actually want to concatenate
this SS 3 yeah and we'll multiply that
ok so then in order to get losses I can
say any dot poses X 0 all right
yeah we don't exactly want to do that
right
no only no bad-mouth eyes are like that
okay so the problem is that some of
these appear in multiple frames and we
only want to let the optimizer alter
them in one kind of way I mean okay I
can certainly fix that with a linear
that's just linear big linear I guess
I'm using side Piper yeah for
optimization I mean okay
okay
all you want that to be a function for
each point we want the frames to be
maybe we could joke it we could create
like a huge house bro we could create
like a huge matrix right that might be
the way to do this as father G to load
us right I could create this massive
matrix where there's only like five
frames so I'm saying let me put like a
frame there if it's valid and the all
five frames can get multiplied by the
point
but that's not exactly right either
because Oh guys life is so hard no that
one's correct it's just really slow
really slow
so I don't actually want any money I
don't care I just like the idea of
making money you know that sounds fun
like something to do a lot of having
things to do
it's probably a better way to phrase
this problem all right guys I gotta go
to work
we'll think about this tomorrow create a
branch get checkout we'll call it G so
right now no what should we name the
optimizer now who knows we're gonna
network this startups are either
worthless or worth billions right I'm
gonna call it something twitch out
whenever we can call things twitch it's
good I wish I could on our million
dollars from twitch man twitch out well
but like readme should go the other one
too
good work tonight guys go work today I
was pushing sergeant we're gonna write a
custom optimizer we're gonna really
continue on this more next time
like tomorrow when we're back on twitch
live streaming with all your bros
alright alright later twitch is about